before we discuss how the recovery from
loads done too early is happening let's
first talk about the store to load
forwarding problem for a load we have to
ask ourselves which earlier store do we
get our value from basically there could
be multiple stores to the same address
that our load is going to and we have to
figure out which store is the one to
supply our value and also if none of
them are matching then we need to figure
that out because then we need to go to
memory when a store is finally resolved
we need to ask ourselves which later
load do I give my value to so there
might be a load whose address is already
known once the store figures out the
address and the value we should be
waking up the load that wants that value
note that there could be multiple loads
that the store needs to give the value
to so where do we figure this out in the
load store queue